"犯罪心理" 前情提要...
Previously on "criminal minds"...
- 惡魔獵人 - 波士頓惡魔獵人?
the reaper. The boston reaper?
- 如果你放過我 我就放過他們 - 我從不和人討價還價
If you stop hunting me, I'll stop hunting them. I don't make deals.
我追捕你這類人
i'm the guy Who hunts guys like you.
你會後悔的
You'll regret this.
你應該與我做交易的
You should have made a deal.
- 你確定我們有危險? - 是的
- Are you sure that we're in danger? - Yes.
告訴他 我會把他們當作親人般守護
Tell them i'll protect them like they're my own.
我不是要離開
I'm not leaving the team,
我只是不再帶領團隊
I'm just no longer in charge.
- 現在由你帶領 - 我?
you are. Me?
George Foyet是第九個受害者 也是唯一從惡魔獵人手中倖免遇難的
George Foyet was the ninth victim And the only one who survived the reaper.
這些傷都是他自己製造的
He inflicted those wounds on himself.
George Foyet就是惡魔獵人
George Foyet is the reaper.
有個囚犯在過去兩天埵洧鴗F兩個信封
One of the inmates has received 2 envelopes in the last 2 days.
我要把這個拿到實驗室
I'll get this to the lab.
他在折磨他
He's torturing him.
見到你侷促不安真是太好了 Hotchner探員
It's great to see you squirm, agent Hotchner.
出去 看看樓下是否需要幫忙
Get out of here.Go see if they need help downstairs.
犯罪心理 第五季 第9集
Criminal Minds S05E09
"對抗惡魔之人"
"he who fights with monsters
"應當心避免自身亦成魔"
"might take care lest he thereby become a monster.
"若你凝望深淵"
"and if you gaze for long into an abyss,
"深淵亦會凝視著你"
The abyss gazes also into you."
Friedrich Nietzsche語 (哲學家尼采)
Friedrich Nietzsche.
請對著錄音機說自己的名字和職務
Please say your name and rank for the record.
特別監督探員Jennifer Jareau
Supervisory special agent jennifer Jareau,
弗吉尼亞州 匡蒂科行為分析科的 公共關係聯絡官
Communications liaison for the behavioral analysis unit In quantico, virginia.
你為行為分析科工作多少年了?
And how long have you been a member of the bau?
六年
6 years.
能大聲點嗎?
Could you speak up, please?
抱歉 六年
sorry. 6 years.
這六年來你一直在Hotchner探員手下工作嗎?
And have you worked under agent Hotchner the entire time?
不 女士 我目前聽命於代理主管Derek Morgan
No, ma'am. i currently Report to acting unit chief Derek Morgan.
他接管了這個部門 是因為Hotchner探員的能力 使得整個團隊的顏面蕩然無存
Who took over the unit because agent Hotchner's Ability to lead the team had become compromised.
我...我認為這不是原因
I--i don't believe that's the reason.
你有不同的觀點?
You have a different opinion?
不只是觀點
It's not just an opinion.
你有不同的理解?
You have a different understanding?
Hotchner探員自願退下來 就能使我們的工作順利進行下去
Ssa Hotchner voluntarily stepped down So we could continue to do our jobs unhindered.
- 你怎麼評價Hotchner探員最近的行為? - 非常努力
- How would you describe agent Hotchner's recent behavior? - Driven.
非常努力 Jareau探員 如果我得不到Hotchner探員
Driven. agent Jareau, your entire team is on the line
對George Foyet調查的足夠信息 你們整個團隊的處境將會十分危險
If i cannot reconcile an adequate account Of agent Hotchner's investigation into George Foyet.
我們那時都在調查惡魔獵人
We were all investigating the reaper.
Hotchner探員只是其中一個人
Ssa Hotchner was not the only one,
尤其是他給我們看了那張名片後
Especially after he sent us that calling card.
他寄給Karl Arnold的報紙文章
The newspaper articles he mailed to karl arnold.
兩封信來自兩個不同的地方
2 letters from 2 different locations.
令我們再次關注此案
They ramped us all back up again.
我開始時就該說的
I should just start at the beginning.
Foyet在最初的一連串殺戮中 給自己製造了很多傷
Foyet had done a lot of injury to himself In the original string of killings,
目的是要裝成受害者 擺脫我們的調查
In an effort to paint himself as a victim And throw us off the investigation.
結果他開始嚴重依賴大量藥性極強的藥物
As a result, he became dependent upon A large number of extremely strong medications.
我們過去一直在全國上下尋找那些 使用多種混合處方的病人
We'd been searching the country for patients With that exact prescription combination,
但是 我們卻不怎麼走運
But we hadn't had any luck.
Foyet寄給Arnold的信封 就要從實驗室送回來了
The envelopes Foyet mailed to arnold are due back from the lab.
上面都標有緊急的符號
They're flagged urgent.
Gina正調查呢
Gina's here with them now.
查過了 非常乾淨 沒指紋 沒DNA
They're processed. clean. no prints, no dna.
她說它們非常乾淨
She says they're clean.
是的 它們當然乾淨
Yeah, of course they are.
Anderson 聽我說
Anderson, listen to me.
我不管你是不是得開車到郵政部長家
I don't care if you have to drive To the postmaster general's house.
我只想在團隊著手之前 知道郵戳是在哪婸\的
I want to know where those postmarks were applied Before the team gets in.
是的 女士 明白
Yes, ma'am. copy that.
找到了
Found it.
他還是不肯喝奶
He's still not taking his bottle.
給我 讓我試試
Here. let me try.
嘿...你能喝奶嗎?
Hey... Can you take your bottle, please?
您能...哦 太謝謝你了
Can you take--oh... Thank you so much.
哦 是的 你真是媽媽的小乖乖 嗯?
Oh, yeah. you are definitely mama's little boy, huh?
就像他老爸一樣
Just like his dady.
下一個
next.
嘿 如果你有事 就走吧
Hey, if you have to go, go ahead.
這些就交給我吧
I can take care of this.
如果我是Hotch 我都不知怎麼辦了
I don't know what i would do if i were in Hotch's shoes.
如果我要跟你和Henry分開 就因為...
If i ever had to say good-bye to you and henry because--
我們哪都不去
We'rnot going anywhere.
我們不會的
We're not.
你在尋找處方 你在尋找郵戳
You're tracking the prescriptions, You're tracking the postmarks.
你已經竭盡所能 無可指責了
Aside from another body landing on your doorstep, You're doing all you can.
為了Hotch 但願如此
I hope so, For Hotch's sake.
- 下一個 - 該我們了
- Next. - That's us.
這是你們的
Here we are.
哦 實際上 應該有兩個處方
Oh, actually, there should be 2 prescriptions.
我們有抗生素 但沒有抗組胺劑
We filled the antibiotics, But we're out of the antihistamine.
你知道麼 碾碎半片克敏能的效果是一樣的
You know, crushing half a claritin Would do the job just the Same.
也給你省了點錢
Save you a couple bucks, too.
等一下...請問
Wait--excuse me,
有許多非處方藥可以替代處方藥嗎?
Are there a lot Of over-the-counter medications That can be substituted for prescriptions?
太多了 數都數不過來
Too many to count.
大多數情況下 只是劑量的問題
Most of the time, it's just a matter of dosage.
Foyet的藥... 我們一直在尋找所有的組合
Foyet's meds--we have been tracking the entire combination.
如果他一直用非處方藥替代其中一些處方藥 來掩飾自己的購買的藥物怎麼辦?
What if he's been using over-the-counter meds For some of it to mask his purchases?
好的 縮小收縮範圍
Ok, narrow the search.
主要看看那些不能替代的藥物 做的不錯
focus on the meds He can't substitute. good work.
郵政部長檢查員辦公室剛打了個電話
just got a call From the postmaster general inspector's office.
這麼快?
Already?
我可不是光說不做的小白臉
I'm not just a pretty face.
能找到Garcia吧
Is garcia in yet?
你不吃嗎?
Are you sure?
燻肉卷 機不可失失不再來啊
Bacon doughnut. you'll never be the Same.
那就讓我華麗地失不再來吧
I can totally think of more palatable ways To up my adventure quotient, thank you.
我..的..天
O...m...g.
每次嘗試都有嶄新的感覺
It gets better every time.
Kevin 你得先出去一下了
Kevin, you need to leave right now.
你需要喝點什麼嗎?
Would you like some water?
不用了 謝謝 長官
No, thank you, ma'am.
你沒事吧
Are you all right?
嗯 我 我只是不太...
I--i'm just not, uh,
不大習慣這種
Comfortable with any of this.
我感覺不好
It's not ok.
你指的什麼?
What do you mean?
在我看來 大家關注的方向錯了
In my opinion, Everyone is asking the wrong questions.
難道沒有人關心開膛手對他們做過什麼
Doesn't anybody care About what the reaper did to them,
他傷害了多少人
How many people he hurt?
人們關心的竟然是...
All anyone seems to care about is...
我不覺得這是正確的
This just isn't right.
你覺得Hotchner探員表現得是否有些...
Do you think that agent Hotchner was acting...
過於激動無法理解
Agitated or unreasonable?
他 不不不 他...
He... No, no, he--
他是擔心他的家人
He was freaked out about his family.
鑒於已經發生的慘劇 我認為是完全可以理解的
Which, considering what happened, I'd say was perfectly reasonable.
Foyet的信分別從弗吉尼亞的弗雷德塈J斯堡
The Foyet letters came from fredericksburg, virginia,
和馬媊鶞澈織絞荋粟S寄來的
And westminster, maryland.
我們需要將兩所城市地圖
We can match the prescription drugs
和Foyet無法找到替代品的處方藥 進行交叉地理側寫
Foyet can't substitute with a geographic profile Of the 2 cities.
無法替代品?
Can't substitute?
你需要找到那些必須由藥劑師經手
We need you to track the drugs that can't be emulated With over-the-counter drugs
沒辦法造假的非處方藥 動作要快
and can only be dispensed By a pharmacist, and you need to do it quickly.
Foyet不會在一個地方久留
Foyet doesn't stay in one place very long.
那我們得讓Kevin留在這
Then Kevin needs to stay.
- 什麼? - 長官 Kevin是個非常出色的分析專家
- What? - ir, Kevin is an amazing analyst.
- 有他幫忙絕對事半功倍 - 那好吧
- I can work almost twice as fast with him running part of my system. - Fine.
- 你用那邊的機器 - Garcia 大概要多久?
- these are your screens. - Garcia, now long?
進入系統之後才能知道
I'll know once i get into it.
我們要先做地理側寫
We're gonna work the geographic profile.
有情況馬上匯報 要快
Call me when you have something. and hurry.
好的 我先從曲馬多找起
Uh, ok... I am gonna start with the ultram--
不 你先從曲馬多和?普生找起 （這兩種均為鎮痛藥）
No--you're gonna start with the ultram and naproxen.
我來找其他的
I'll work on the rest.
從弗雷德塈J斯堡到威斯敏斯特大概有115英里
There's approximately 115 miles Between fredericksburg and westminster.
為什麼從兩個城市寄信呢
Why mail a letter from 2 cities?
可能是心理戰術
Maybe it's purely a forensic countermeasure.
他知道在家附近寄信會引火燒身
He knows that mailing letters close to home would lead us right to him,
所以開車大老遠跑去寄信以甩掉我們的視線
So he drives far away to mail the letters to throw us off his scent.
郵件炸彈客和01年炭疽襲擊都是如此
The unabomber did that. so did the 2001 anthrax suspect.
他也可以選其他地方 但他還是在特區周圍作案
He could have gone anywhere, but he's trolling the d.c. area.
這說明他還是要接近Hotch
It makes sense to stay close to Hotch.
他曾逗留在波士頓附近 監視Shaunessy警官的惡化情況
He stuck around boston to watch shaunessy deteriorate.
- 不 我不是說你... - 沒關係
- Not that you're-- - It's all right.
我知道他在監視我
i know he's been watching me.
這也是我自願降職的部分原因
It's part of the reason i stepped down,
讓他認為我已經精神崩潰
So he'd think i was falling apart.
大多數非處方藥局都可以開到?普生 (抗炎鎮痛藥)
Naproxen is available in generic brands over the counter.
?普生鈉緩釋片堶惆膃?普生的藥性
Naproxen's properties can be simulated by aleve.
曲馬多也可以找到替代品
Ultram can be substituted.
好的 再找奧施康定 (另一種鎮痛藥品)
Ok, oxycontin.
天 他還用這個?
Jeez, he's on that, too?
沒錯 不過這個藥品很容易上癮 所以產量被限制
Yeah, and it's highladdictive and therefore regulated,
所以無法找到替代品
So there's no substitute for it.
我知道藥監局管得嚴
I know the dea has a problem with it.
但有門路的話還是能買得到
You can buy it on the streets if you know where to go.
的確如此 既然這玩意兒能從其他渠道搞來
Good point. ok, we're gonna leave that off the list for now
那麼就先不在這個名單上面找它了
'cause there's another way to get it.
下一個  甲巰咪唑
next up...Tapazole.
那是什麼?
What's that?
它是治療甲狀腺功能亢進的
Uh, it treats hyperthyroidism.
嗨 到底這傢伙得的什麼病啊
Hey, what's wrong with this guy, anyway?
他喜歡自己捅自己玩兒
He stabbed himself--a lot.
捅自己?
Stabbed himself?
是 所以他遍體鱗傷
Yeah. so his body would have permanent internal damage--
親愛的 別停啊 所以他需要這些處方藥保證他的心率正常
Work, honey--and he'd need This prescription to regulate his heart rate,
降低心悸和震顫
Keep down the palpitations and the tremors.
甲疏咪唑沒有可替代藥品
And there is no substitute for tapazole.
如果咱們少了這一個 怎麼能找出他呢
So if this is our missing link, how do we find him?
把兩個城市方圓60英里所有用這個處方的人 都打印出來
Print out every person who's on this prescription Within a 60-mile of both cities.
剩下的工作交給他們
the team will do the rest.
我得用一下你的手提電腦
I'm gonna use your laptop.
兩個城市 我們怎麼辦
Ok, so what are we gonna do about the 2 cities?
咱們地理側寫一般不是都需要三個地點 才能準確進行定位的嗎
Usually we need 3 different points to get an accurate geographic profile.
可是現在只有兩個
That's all we got right now.
蓋瑟斯堡 羅克韋爾 首府特區 亞歷山德堥
Gaithersburg, Rockville, D.c., Alexandria,
包伊 安納波利斯
Bowie, Annapolis.
Foyet 你到底在哪
Where the hell are you, Foyet?
我和那小子一起找到一個沒辦法買到 非處方藥代替的甲狀腺藥品
Ok, me and the boy found a thyroid medication That has no substitute over the counter.
必須要從藥劑師那媔}
You've gotta get it from a pharmacist.
但是很多人都需要開這個藥
But a lot of people are on it.
找到兩個地方的中間點 縮小到方圓25英里內的名字呢
Find the midpoint between the 2 cities And isolate names in a 25-mile radius.
153個
153 names.
他肯定不會用真名
Well, he's not gonna use his own name.
那他一般會用什麼名字
What kind of aliases should we be looking for?
他可以直接盜用他人的身份
He could have easily stolen someone's identity.
不會的 他是個極度自我陶醉的殺人狂
No, he's a narcissist in love with his own mythology.
他肯定會用與案情有關的名字
He'd use a name connected with the case.
受害者 或者 警察
A victim, maybe, a cop.
咱們看一下Foyet的檔案 找一下死者名單
Ok. let's check the Foyet files For a list of names.
沒有結果
and...Nothing.
等一下 Foyet喜歡一些對他有意義的東西
Wait a minute, guys. Foyet likes things to have meaning to him.
那只象徵上帝的眼睛
The eye of providence,
把我們引向他的那個 公車上面的血書地址
The addresses in blood he wrote on the bus that led us back to him.
可能他取別名也是如此
Maybe he's doing the Same thing with the alias.
就像是字母排序之類的那種把戲
Like an anagram or something.
Reid 有什麼發現嗎?
You see something, Reid?
還沒有
Not yet.
Reid 他自稱是開膛手
Reid, he named himself the reaper.
Peter Rhea
Peter Rhea.
阿靈頓有一個Peter Rhea
There's a Peter Rhea in arlington.
找到了
we found him.
在找到George Foyet可能居住的地方後
Once the team located George Foyet's potential apartment,
為什麼BAU小組沒有立即採取行動
Why didn't the bau enter immediately?
- Rossi探員 - 嗯
- Agent Rossi? - Hmm?
我問話呢
I asked you a question.
金價還在升
Gold is still going up.
但什麼時候拋出 就是奧妙所在
But knowing when to get out, that's the trick.
你在說什麼
What are you doing?
Erin 這樣做有什麼意義?
What's the point of all this, erin?
為什麼?
Why?
確保不再發生類似情況
So this never happens again.
局堥S有任何人能夠 確保此類事情不會再次發生
There is nothing a bureaucrat can do To make sure that something like this never happens again.
難道我們就坐等下次血案?
So we just wait for the next bloodbath?
你們在進Foyet的公寓之前 為什麼要等那麼久?
Why did you wait so long before going to Foyet's apartment?
我們要確定他在堶
We had to be sure he was there.
如果我們貿然進去 而他不在的話 會打草驚蛇
If we went in and he wasn't, He would know we found him.
誠然 我們等得越久 他越有機會...
Of course, the longer we waited, The more time he had to...
這是個棘手的抉擇
It was an impossible decision.
那麼是誰作出抉擇的?
So who made it?
Hotchner探員嗎?
Agent Hotchner?
我們等了多久了
How much longer do we wait?
決策權不在我手上
I need to leave that call to someone else.
突襲隊已經等得不耐煩了
Swat's getting antsy.
他們該進去的時候我自然會發話
I'll tell them when it's time to go.
現在 告訴他們在原地老實呆著
Right now we sit tight. let them know.
那群人擅長的可不是原地待命而是突圍啊
These guys are trained to move, not just sit around.
我也不怪他們
I can't really say that i blame them.
可能他已經不在那堣F
He may not even be there anymore.
我知道 有可能我們在這塈今左贖 他人已經逃之夭夭了
I know. the longer we sit here, the further away he gets.
孩子 你已經做了你能做的了
You make the best call you can, kid.
那我們現在這樣
All right, this is what we're gonna do.
我是管理員
Super.
你的樓上漏水
There's a leak in the apartment above you.
我得檢查一下你是否受到影響
I need to check your ceiling.
你們收到信號了嗎
Are you getting the signal?
收到
Copy.
堶惆S有人
No warm bodies.
看上去是廚房 有桌椅
Looks like kitchen table, chair.
桌子上面的是電腦嗎
Is that a laptop on the table?
這個可能有用
It could be useful.
那個是食物嗎?把鏡頭拉近
is that food? get closer to that.
等等 拉遠 地上是什麼
Wait, go back. what's that on the floor?
是他的信件
Yeah. it's his mail.
行動 快
Go, go, go, go!
快 立即行動
Hurry up! let's go!
怎麼了?
What happened?
他不會再回來了 食物都沒動過
He's not coming back here. he left an untouched meal.
只有在驚慌失措的情況下才會 把郵件亂扔在地上
You drop your mail like this when you're startled,
或者在要馬上逃跑的時候
When you need to get out of dodge quick.
他知道我們要來這 有什麼提醒了他
Something tipped him off. he knew we were coming here.
箱子開著 堶惘陷X件衣服不見了
Suitcases are open, some clothes are missing.
保險箱堶惘陪蚋繳j的地方
There's a safe with a stash of guns in it.
他連鎖都不上了
He didn't even bother to lock them up again.
如果他真的很著急 那就會出錯
If he's in a hurry, he'll make a mistake.
可是一旦Foyet狗急跳牆 他就開始殺人了
Yeah, but when Foyet gets cornered, He starts killing.
我們不能讓這發生
We're not gonna let that happen.
我們得馬上聯繫Garcia
We need to get garcia on this.
他真是很厲害
He is creepy good.
有多厲害?
How good?
他把硬盤全部清空了 可能走得很急
He wiped his hard drive. might have been in a hurry to leave,
不過這也說明硬盤堶悸漯F西都是不可見人的
But whatever was on there, he did not want us to see it.
Garcia 跟我說你能進入系統還原數據
Garcia, tell me that you're hacked in and that you can rebuild it.
親愛的 看著吧
Watch me work, darling.
- 還在嗎? - 有什麼發現
- Hello. - What have you got?
他用Peter Rhea的名字註冊了 一個網絡安全報警器
He had an internet alarm on the name Peter Rhea.
一旦我們開始查 他就會知道
It alerted him as soon as we ran a check on it.
他還刪掉了什麼
What else did he wipe?
Garcia 等等 回到剛才那張圖片
Garcia, wait a minute. freeze it right there.
- 哦上帝 那不是... - 那是負責保護我家人的法警
Oh, my god, isn't that-- That's the u.s. marshal assigned to my family.
Foyet這麼長時間以來一直在監視他
Foyet's been watching him this whole time?
Kass Meyer 請留言
KassMeyer. leave a message.
Sam  是我Aaron 我們找到Foyet的位置了
Sam, it's Aaron. we found Foyet's location,
不過他有監視你的照片
But he has surveillance photos of you.
咱們找地方見一面 或者我們現在去找你
Call me for a meet location or we're on our way to you.
我們得徵調另一支特別行動組
We're gonna need to deploy another swat unit.
那需要半個小時
That's gonna take another half hour.
Hotch
Hotch?
咱們走
Go. go.
你們馬上就去了法警Kass Meyer家
You left for marshal KassMeyer's house immediately?
是的 長官
Yes, ma'am.
你不知道這是戰略應對小組的工作嗎
Wouldn't this be a job for a tactical team?
我們覺得再去申請授權調派 另一支隊伍會浪費很多時間
We felt that it would take too much time To get authorization for another operation.
- "我們"? - 我們所有人
- We? - All of us.
你確定不是Hotchner探員讓你們這麼做的?
Don't you mean agent Hotchner wanted that?
不 我是說我們所有人想法一致
No, i mean all of us wanted that.
我知道你怎麼想
I know what you're thinking,
我也同意 如果只處分他一個人 對我們其他人都會好些
And i agree it would be easy for us to blame him.
好些?
Easy?
是啊 要是像你說的一切都是他的錯 一切都了結了
Yeah. why not just say it's his fault And then we can all just forget about it.
但是 問題在於
But, uh, the problem is,
我的腦子清楚得很 (不像你老糊塗)
I have an eidetic memory,
事實並不是那樣
And that's not what happened.
Sam
Sam.
我是FBI的探員Rossi 我們需要救護車
This is agent Rossi, fbi. we need an ambulance.
這埵酗@個聯邦調查員受傷了
We have a federal officer down.
我不會...我不會...
I wouldn't...i wouldn't...
我們已經叫了救護車
We're getting an ambulance.
- 堅持住 - 我盡力了
- hang on. - I tried.
- 一定要挺住 - 我很抱歉
- Just hang on. - I'm sorry.
你為什麼要道歉?
What are you sorry for?
我已經...已經盡力了
I...i tried.
Jack和Haley現在安全嗎?
Are Jack and Haley safe?
Sam 告訴我發生了什麼事
Sam, tell me what happened.
我不知道他怎麼進來的
I don't know how he got in.
他們在哪?
Where are they?
我不知道你在說什麼
I don't know what you're talking about.
我總歸會知道的... 不管用什麼辦法
I'm gonna find out... One way or another.
Sam 我不是很明白
Sam, i need to understand.
他知道Jack和Haley在哪麼?
Does he know where Jack and Haley are?
我沒有...
I didn't...
這個小玩意兒...
This little piggy...
看看這個 他是我的了 不是麼?
Look at that. he's not going anywhere, is he?
她的電話是多少? 她的保密電話是多少?
What about her phone number? what's her safe phone number?
我沒有...這已經不重要了
I didn't...it won't matter.
殺了我吧 我什麼都不會說的
Kill me. i'm not telling you anything.
沒那麼容易
You're not gonna get off that easy.
我要你活著去告訴Hotchner探員 是他一手造成了他家人的死
I need you alive so you can tell agent Hotchner That it's his fault that his family's dead.
我 我盡力了 Hotch
I--i tried, Hotch.
他的兩腿和一腳掌受到槍擊
Gunshot wounds to each leg, one foot,
幾隻手指折斷 被暴力毆打過
He's missing several fingers, and appears to be badly beaten.
讓開
Clear out of the way.
給我拿個頸托 在搶救的時候準備好鹽水
Get me a c-collar, prep me a saline drip While i grab a round of vitals.
Sam 你有對什麼藥物過敏嗎?
Sam, are you allergic to any medication?
Hotch
Hotch.
Sam 我在
Sam, i'm right here.
我盡力了
I tried.
確保有外科醫生隨時待命
Make sure they have a trauma surgeon standing by.
你是否相信是Kassmeyer警官的過錯 導致了Hotch家人遇險?
do you believe it was marshal KassMeyer's fault That agent Hotchner's family was compromised?
當然不是
Absolutely not.
你回答得很快啊
You answered that very quickly.
當你被嚴刑拷打時 只有說出實情 才能停止這種折磨
When you're being tortured, there's no end in sight, Except giving them what they want.
而Kassmeyer沒這麼做?
And KassMeyer didn't do that?
他忍受了Foyet給的一切折磨
He withstood everything that Foyet had.
把實情一字一句地告訴我
Then tell me exactly what happened.
- 他還醒著麼? - 要麼進去要麼走開
- Is he conscious? - In and out.
Sam 我是Aaron
Sam, it's Aaron.
你聽得到麼?
Can you hear me?
- Aaron - 我就在這 sam
- Aaron. - I'm right here, Sam.
他血壓在下降
His pressure's dropping.
注射10cc嗎啡
10cc morphine going in.
不要給我用嗎啡 我要保持清醒
Do not sedate me. i need to talk.
Sam Foyet知不知道Jack和Haley在哪?
Sam, does Foyet know where Jack and Haley are?
我沒有告訴他 但已經晚了
I wouldn't tell him. it doesn't matter.
讓我猜猜看
Let me guess.
法警不會以人名排序
The marshals service Doesn't have anything listed by name.
只會用案子代碼而已
Case numbers only.
問題是
The thing is,
這種排序是帶有個人喜好的
This relocation is a bit of a special favor,
也就是說你在家也得辦公
Which tells me that you might bring your work home with you.
誰知道呢? 或許在快速撥號的名單上
Who knows? maybe even on emergency speed dial.
你好 是Haley嗎?
Hello, Haley?
不好意思 打錯了
I'm sorry. wrong number.
你好 是Haley嗎?
Hello, is Haley there?
呃 不好意思
Uh, uh, no, ma'am. i'm sorry.
我打錯了
It must have been a wrong number.
你好 是Haley嗎?
Hello, is Haley there?
你好 Haley?
Hello, Haley?
是Haley嗎?
Hello, is Haley there?
- Sam? - Haley
- Sam? - Haley.
Hal...
Ohh--hal--
不好意思用了你的真名
Sorry for using your real name, ma'am.
我叫Victor Collins 是聯邦執法局的
My name is victor collins. i'm with the marshals service.
夫人 我們有麻煩了
Ma'am, we have a problem.
Kassmeyer警官被謀殺了
Marshal KassMeyer has been killed,
- 我們擔心你的地址也被暴露了 - 什麼?
- And we're afraid your location may have been compromised. - What?
夫人 請仔細聽好 這關係到你兒子的安危
Ma'am, i need you to focus right now. this is about saving your son.
我們正努力保護Jack 你明白麼?
We're trying to save Jack. do you understand me?
是的
Yes.
我擔心這還沒完 夫人
I'm afraid there's more, ma'am.
我不知道該怎麼開口 但是...
I'm not quite sure how to tell you this, but...
你前夫也被謀殺了...
Your ex-husband has been killed as well.
噢 天吶
Oh, god.
我們會帶你和你孩子去安全的地方
We're gonna bring you and your son in safe,
但同時需要你的配合 行嗎?
But i'm gonna need your help for this, ok?
我們打完這通電話後
When we're through speaking, i want you to hang up the phone.
不要打給任何人
Do not attempt to call anybody else.
- 明白了嗎? 你的電話可能會被監聽 - 知道了
- Do you understand me? it could be intercepted. - Yes.
然後去買個可拋式手機
The next thing i need you to do Is buy a disposable cell phone.
接著回到車 用新的手機打給我
Get back in your car, call me at this number.
當我拿到你的號碼後 我再給你個新的號
Once i know your mobile, i'll give you another number
- 隨後告訴你接下來怎麼做 - 好的
- Along with some instructions on how to proceed. - Ok.
夫人 我不想讓你太過擔心
Now, ma'am, i do not want you to worry.
我們會保證你和Jack的安全
We're gonna bring you and Jack in here safely.
你...你確定Aaron已經...?
Are you... Are you sure Aaron is...
- 你確定麼? - 是的 夫人
- Are you sure? - Yes, ma'am.
我很遺憾
I'm terribly sorry.
再見了
See you later.
好吧
Ok.
她正自投羅網
She's going to him.
我很抱歉 Hotch
I'm so sorry, Hotch.
他們正等著你
They're ready for you.
Prentiss探員
Agent Prentiss.
長官
Ma'am.
我們瞭解到Hotchner探員 故意讓自己脫離隊伍 單獨行動
We understand that agent Hotchner Managed to separate himself from the rest of the team.
他沒有"故意"這麼做
He didn't "manage" to do that.
當Kassmeyer警官在救護車堮
When marshal KassMeyer was in the ambulance--
Hotchner探員主動陪同他
Agent Hotchner volunteered to ride along.
在他失去意識前瞭解實情
To get answers before he lost consciousness.
你為什麼不去?
Why didn't you go with him?
我認為沒這必要
It didn't seem necessary.
他這樣和你說的?
Did you tell you that?
這就是你的目的?
Is that what you're looking for,
找一個指控他的罪名?
A way to blame this on him?
這麼做有什麼好處?
What good could that possibly do?
Hotchner探員一直在尋找 脫離隊伍 單獨行動的機會
Agent Hotchner was looking for an opportunity To separate himself from the team
- 顯然 他做到了 - 這不是事實
- and he found one. - That isn't true.
他不顧一切 孤注一擲 並且不想有人攔住他
He was desperate and he didn't want someone With a clear head to stop him.
這有什麼問題?
Is there a question in there somewhere?
告訴我Hotchner探員在救護車堮 你們在幹什麼
Tell me what happened while agent Hotchner was in the ambulance.
我們聯繫了聯邦執法局
We contacted the u.s. marshals.
他們說Haley失蹤了
They said Haley was in the wind.
她扔掉了手機 所以無法找到她
She had dumped her cell phone, So there was no way to track her.
Hotchner探員對此有什麼反應?
And how did agent Hotchner react to that news?
Foyet通過Kassmeyer的電話打給Haley
Foyet called Haley from KassMeyer's phone.
好的 我去讓Garcia跟蹤線路 JJ
All right, we'll get garcia to trace it. JJ.
他告訴她說 她的行蹤已經暴露 並且我被謀殺了
He told her she was compromised and i was dead.
你打過給她嗎?
Well, have you called her?
沒 他讓她扔掉手機去買個新的
No. he said to throw her phone away and to buy a disposable.
Hotch 我們這就來接你
Hotch, we're gonna come get you right now.
不需要了 Anderson會把車開來的
No, anderson's bringing me a car.
那我們在辦公室見?
You want to meet back at the office?
我只是希望她至少會打個電話來確認一下
I'm hoping that she's just gonna call me, at least, to check.
Foyet假裝是法警 並通過 Haley熟悉的號碼聯繫她
Foyet posed as a marshal, even called from a number that Haley recognized.
並且斷了她打給Hotchner的念頭 嚇住了她
And then he did what gets him off. he scared her.
不 他麻痹了她 搞定了她
no, he paralyzed her. he overwhelmed her.
現在她對他是完全信任 你認為他會把Haley帶到哪去?
And now she trusts him. where do you think he would take her?
證人保護組在新澤西為她提供了住所
Witness protection had her living in new jersey.
要是他立刻動身的話 可能已經到了
He has a head start. he could be there now.
Garcia有線索了
Garcia's got a trace.
他就在幾個塔覆蓋的範圍內
He's bouncing between a few towers.
- 哪? - 費爾非克斯郡(維吉尼亞州)
- Where? - Fairfax county.
他還在這?
He's still local?
將坐標發到我手機上
Send the coordinates to my phone.
好了
Done.
他幹嗎還不去新澤西?
Why isn't he on his way to new jersey?
等等 那電話開著?
Wait, that phone's on?
是的
Yes.
- Hotch? - 他掛斷了
- Hotch? - He hung up.
該死的
Damn it.
怎麼了?
What's that?
Hotch正打給Foyet
Hotch is calling Foyet.
Hotchner探員
Agent Hotchner.
要是你敢動她一根毫毛的話...
If you touch her...
溫柔點嘛 就像我對你一樣
Be gentle, like i was with you?
你怎麼用了那麼久?
What the hell took you so long?
我還以為手機出問題了呢
I was beginning to think this phone was dead or something.
怎麼那麼安靜?
Why so quiet?
你懊惱時應該破口大罵才對
You usually lash out when you're frustrated.
我沒懊惱 你並不難找
I'm not frustrated. you're more predictable than you think.
是麼?
Am i?
你不知道Haley在哪
You didn't know where Haley was,
所以你讓她來找你
So you made her come to you.
你說得我很懶一樣
You make me sound lazy.
你只是想展示下你的控制力而已
Just another way for you to show control.
噢 那可太糟了
Oh, that's terrible.
你媽媽想讓你遠離你爸的威脅 但她還不夠強壯
You're mother tried to protect you from your father, But she wasn't strong enough.
你懷恨至今 是不是?
And you hated her for that, didn't you?
你認為所有的女人都很贏弱
You decided that all women were weak.
這可是你說的 不是我
Those are your words, not mine.
你殺掉他們的時候才9歲吧?
What were you, 9 when you killed them?
那只是場交通事故
It was a car accident.
你並沒有因為這件事 而受到表揚
That you couldn't take credit for. That had to be hard for you.
但是可憐的George又有了次機會
But poor George got another chance.
這個被遺棄的小孩被一對富有但卻無法生育的 東部夫婦所收養 Foyet一家
The little orphan was saved By the wealthy, sterile eastside couple, the Foyets.
故事本該就此結束
And the story should have ended there.
我不相信童話故事 你呢?
I don't believe in fairy tales. do you?
問題是 George 這可不是童話故事
That's the thing, George. this isn't a fairy tale.
你不必書寫這故事
You don't have to write this story.
你什麼都不必做
You don't have to do any of this.
我知道你已經精疲力盡了
I know you're exhausted.
總是回頭看
Always looking over your shoulder,
總在想到底什麼時候才是終點?
Always wondering when the other shoe is gonna drop.
你難道還沒得到你想要的麼?
Haven't you gotten what you wanted?
你讓你自己變得和其他人與眾不同
You've set yourself apart from anybody we've ever dealt with.
你不僅僅是個連環殺手 你是屠夫
You're not just a famous serial killer, you're the reaper.
我們將研究你這個案例很多年
We're gonna study you and your methods for years and years.
你知道我一直在想什麼嗎?
You know what i've been thinking?
Haley一頭黑髮看上去真是楚楚動人啊
Haley looks pretty good with dark hair.
她好像變瘦了
She's lost some weight.
一定是你給她帶來了太多壓力
Must be all the stress you caused her.
小傢伙在哪呢?
Where's the little man?
看到他了
Oh. there he is.
他喜歡美國隊長是受你的影響嗎? (美國漫畫堛漱@個角色)
Does he like captain america because of you?
你妻子打來的
That's your wife.
等一下哦
Hold, please.
Hotchner太太
Mrs. Hotchner.
我來了
I'm here.
打開大門讓我進去吧
Open the gate and i'll drive in.
好的
Ok.
Aaron?
我先掛了
I really gotta go.
你還沒查到Foyet在哪嗎?
and you still didn't know where Foyet was?
那手機屬於美國聯邦執法局
The phone belonged to a U.S. Marshal.
特殊設計過 能避過信號塔
It was designed to bounce between towers,
所以無法定位他的具體位置
So we could not pinpoint his location.
Hotchner探員就那樣漫無目的地 開著車四處找?
And agent Hotchner was driving around aimlessly.
不
No.
他沒有
He wasn't.
我們有Foyet的側寫
We had Foyet's profile,
我們知道只要跟隨側寫 就會知道他把Hotch的家人帶到哪
And we knew if we followed it, We would know were he took Hotch's family.
好的 Foyet喜歡掌控一切
All right, Foyet has to be in control.
他讓Haley主動找他
He had Haley come to him.
沒錯 但他會把她帶到哪去?
Yeah, but where would he take her?
他希望Hotch能找到他 去看看他身處什麼地方
He'd want Hotch to find him, to see where he was,
- 看著他做了什麼 - 也就是說...
- to see what he did. - Which means he--
他和Hotch通話的時候有透露關於地點的線索
He said something on that call That tells Hotch where to go.
Reid 他都說了些什麼?
Reid, what did he say, exactly?
"Haley一頭黑髮看上去真是楚楚動人啊 她好像變瘦了
"Haley's hair looks good dark. she's lost some weight.
一定是因為你給她帶來的壓力
"it must be because of all the stress you caused her.
小傢伙在哪呢?看到他了
"where's the little man? oh, there he is now.
你覺得他喜歡美國隊長是受你的影響嗎?
"do you think he likes captain america because of you?
你妻子打來的電話 等一下
"that's your wife on the other line. hold, please.
嗨 打開大門讓我進去
Hi. open the gate and i'll drive in."
打開大門?
Open the gate?
那一定是一個能對Hotch 造成強烈情感衝擊的地方
It would be someplace With the biggest emotional impact for Hotch.
而且Haley能控制大門
And Haley has access to the gate.
是他們的房子 他們一起居住的地方
Their house, where they lived together.
沒錯 Foyet早就預謀好的
Of course. Foyet planned this all the way to the end.
這是他最想要的
It's everything to him.
他想控制Hotch的家 顯示自己的支配地位
He wants to take over Hotch's home To be in control to prove his dominance.
Morgan
Morgan.
- 他要去你家 - 我知道
- He's going to your house. - I know.
Hotch 我正派出戰略部隊
I'm sending out a full tactical deployment, Hotch.
- 好 - 我們正趕過來
- Good. - We're on our way.
Foyet在打給Hotch
Foyet's calling Hotch.
Garcia 能讓我們聽到嗎?
Garcia, can you get us on?
Foyet
Foyet.
Aaron?
你沒事?
You're ok?
我很好
I'm fine.
但是...他說過...
But... He said that...
天啊 Aaron
Oh, Aaron.
- 他能聽到我們的對話 是嗎? - 是的
- He can hear us, right? - Yes.
我很抱歉
I am so sorry.
Haley 別示弱 別害怕
Haley, show him no weakness, No fear.
我知道
I know.
Sam給我說過所有關於他的事
Sam told me all about him.
- 他... - Sam沒事
- Is he, uh-- - No, Sam is fine.
Aaron Aaron Aaron
Aaron, Aaron, Aaron.
這就是你婚姻失敗的原因吧? 因為你總是撒謊
Is that why your marriage broke up, Because you're a liar?
Haley 別聽他的
Don't listen to him, Haley.
Sam的智能手機在我手上
I have Sam's service phone right here.
他們剛群發短信公佈他的死訊
They sent out a mass text about his death.
你可以自己看看
You can take a look if you want.
他只是想嚇你
He's trying to scare you.
你沒告訴過她 這到底是怎麼回事吧?
Did you even tell her what this was about?
沒說過那交易的事吧
About the deal?
他只是想激怒你
He's just trying to make you angry.
她應該生氣啊 她會...
Well, she should be. she's gonna...
死翹翹
D-i-e
全拜你高傲的自尊心所賜
Because of your inflated ego.
Haley 別理他
Ignore him, Haley.
我知道你不希望她知道真相
I'm sure you don't want her to know this part either.
你知道嗎 只要他肯放棄追捕我
You know, all he had to do was stop looking for me
你就不會落到這個地步
And you wouldn't be in this mess.
別回應他
Don't react.
他在說什麼?
What is he talking about?
告訴Jack 我需要他協助我辦案
Tell Jack i need him working the case.
什麼?
What?
告訴Jack 我需要他協助我辦案
Tell Jack i need him working the case.
Jack
Jack.
你聽到嗎?
Did you he that?
嗨 爸爸
Hi, daddy.
嗨 小傢伙
Hi, buddy.
George是壞人嗎?
Is George a bad guy?
是的 他是壞人
Yes, he is.
Jack 我需要你協助我辦案
Jack, i need you on this case with me.
聽明白了嗎?
Do you understand?
我需要你和我一樣辦案
I need you to work the case with me.
好的 爸爸
Ok, daddy.
Jack 替我抱一下媽媽
Jack, hug your mom for me.
媽媽抱得我好緊
Mommy hug me too tight.
對不起
I'm sorry.
你為什麼難過呢?
Why are you sad?
我只是太愛你了
Oh, i just love you so much.
媽媽 我要走啦 我得辦案呢
Mommy, i gotta go. i'm working the case.
好的
Ok.
他真可愛
He's so cute.
就像FBI小小實習生一樣
He's like a little junior g-man.
我等會來找你哦 Jackie寶寶
I'll be right up, Jackie boy!
- 他走了嗎? - 是的
- Is he gone? - Yes.
Haley 你很堅強 比我堅強多了
You're so strong, Haley. you're stronger than i ever was.
你會盡快過來的 是嗎?
You'll hurry, right?
我知道你不該經受這一切
I know you didn't sign on for this.
你也是
Neither did you.
我一直有負於你
I'm sorry for everything.
答應我 告訴他我們是怎麼相遇的
Promise me that you will tell him how we met
告訴他 你以前怎麼逗我笑
And how you used to make me laugh.
Haley...
Aaron 要讓他知道 你不是一直都這麼嚴肅
He needs to know that you weren't always so serious, Aaron.
我希望他能相信愛 因為這是世上最重要的東西
I want him to believe in love, Because it is the most important thing.
但你一定要表現給他看
But you need to show him.
答應我
Promise me.
我答應你
I promise.
我不知道之後發生了什麼事
And i don't know what happened after that.
等我結果了你之後
After i finish you...
我會找到你那小雜種
I'm gonna find that little bastard son of yours
我要給他看看親生父母的屍體
And i'm gonna show him both of his dead parents,
我會告訴他 這都是你的錯
And i'm gonna tell him that it was all your fault.
然後我會...
And them i'm gonna--
好啦 你抓...你抓到我了
Ok. you got--you got me.
我投降
I surrender.
Hotch! Hotch!
他死了
He's dead.
Hotch 停手 快停手
Hotch, stop. come on, stop it.
都結束了
It's over.
沒事了 都過去了 兄弟
It's ok. it's over, man.
你在做什麼呢?
what are you doing?
我和你一起辦案啊 爸爸 (case的含義既有盒子也有案件)
I work the case with you, dad.
Jack 很高興你能陪我辦案
Jack, i'm glad you're working the case with me.
我總是用得上你的幫忙
You know i can always use your help.
我在辦案 爸爸 就像你說的那樣
I work the case daddy, just like you said.
你做得很好 孩子
You did a great job, buddy.
爸爸 你怎麼了?
What happened to you, daddy?
我沒事 出去和Jareau呆在一起好嗎?
I'm ok. i want you to go outside with Ms. Jareau. ok?
過來 寶貝
Come here, sweetheart.
我很抱歉 Hotch
I'm so sorry, Hotch.
出去吧 看看樓下是否需要幫忙
Get out of here. go see if they need help downstairs.
我已經無法再為她做什麼
There was nothing i could do for her.
她已經....
She was already...
她走得很快
She died fairly quickly.
其中一個傷口切斷了大動脈
One of the wounds severed her aorta,
他們認為她...
And they don't think that she...
認為她沒受多少痛苦
And they don't think she suffered much.
Hotchner探員 要是當時George Foyet從那堬璅
Agent Hotchner, what do you think would have happened If George Foyet had gotten up from that floor?
要是你沒殺死他 你覺得事情會變成怎樣?
If you didn't kill him?
根本不需要想 我知道他會 想辦法把我兒子也殺掉
I don't have to think. i know he would have tried to kill my son, too.
我沒問題了
That's good enough for me.
你們還有問題嗎?
Any questions?
Hotchner探員
Agent Hotchner.
我對你的損失深表遺憾
I'm so sorry for your loss.
要是...你或你的兒子需要什麼...
And... If you or your son need anything...
謝謝
Thank you.
詩人Haniel Long曾說過
poet Haniel Long said,
"我們心堻怓好的就是對家人的愛"
"so much of what is best in us "is bound up in our love of family
"因為它能保持我們的安定"
"that it remains the measure of our stability
"因為它能衡量我們的忠誠"
Because it measures our sense of loyalty."
犯罪心理 第五季 第9集
== 結束 ==
Criminal Minds S05E09